We continue our discussion of the U.S.-Iran war
我们继续讨论正在进行的美伊战争
that is happening right now.
正如你所知，我做出了预测
So, as you know, I made the prediction
So, as you know, Imade the prediction
that the United States will lose this war.
美国将会输掉这场战争。
And last class, we did an overview of the military
上节课，我们对军事实力与战略位置做了概览。
and strategic position.
And today,
今天，
we're going to provide some theoretical framework for
我们将为
how to understand how this war will progress
如何理解这场战争的进展提供一些理论框架
and why, ultimately, I believe the United States will lose this war.
以及为什么，最终我认为美国会输掉这场战争。
Today, I present to you a very important idea in game theory.
今天，我向你们介绍一个非常重要的博弈理论概念。
And once you understand this idea,
一旦你们理解了这个概念，
you understand why things will turn out the way they do.
你明白为什么事情会按那样发展。
It's called a law of asymmetry.
这叫不对称定律。
Law. of asymmetry
不对称定律。
and
和
all this is saying is that
这全部的意思是
the United States and
美国和
Iran are not peers they're not
伊朗不是同级的，他们不是同等的。
equals the United States is far stronger than Iran
美国远比伊朗强大。
and we should expect the United States to overwhelm
我们应该预料美国会压倒伊朗。
and destroy Iran really easily the law asymmetry states
并且轻易摧毁伊朗，非对称法则说
that that's usually not the case it's usually underdog
那通常不是这样，通常是弱者
that has the advantage
那弱者拥有优势
and
和
we see this from history all the time okay
我们从历史中看到这一点，时间都一样，好的
so when the Persians in about 490
于是当波斯人在大约490年
BC invaded mainland Greece against Athens
BC入侵希腊本土对抗雅典
and Sparta Persia at this time at that
以及斯巴达，波斯在此时已是...
time was the first world empire infinite
此时是第一大帝国，万无穷
resources infinite mental resources and the only reason that Persia was able to conquer the Greek Empire was because of the power of the Persians and
资源无穷，正是波斯人的力量让他们能征服希腊帝国，且波斯人拥有无穷的财富与力量
the power of the Persians and the power of the Persians and the power of the Persians and power infinite wealth and it lost to the Greeks not once
波斯人的力量、波斯人的力量、波斯人的力量、波斯人的力量以及无穷的财富，正是他们能征服希腊的原因
but twice and and then
两次而非一次，随后又…
the Macedonians under exit in the Greek and
马其顿人在希腊时期的统治下
they were like a tribal army not a very large army they were able to go into Persia
他们像部落军队，规模不大，却能进攻波斯
and Persia at the time was basically most of Eurasia
当时波斯基本占领欧亚大陆
and conquered it in about ten years time
并在大约十年内征服它
the Romans started off as a tribal people
罗马人最初是部落民族
which then built the Mediterranean Empire
随后便建立了地中海帝国
then you have the ex -ex you have so
然后你就有了前后两次的出现，接着是…
the Vikings so
维京人，呃…
this happens a lot in human history a
这种情况在人的历史里经常出现
people in the borderlands a tribe a
边境人群，部落民族，少数民族能征服大帝国
small ethnicity are able to conquer a great empire
以及不对称定律告诉我们原因。
and the law asymmetry tells us why okay
so I'm gonna go over the very slowly in detail
于是我会慢慢细细讲一遍
how this law symmetry asymmetry works all right
这条对称律是怎么运作的，先说说吧
so let's look at an empire
那我们先来看看一个帝国
and
和
there are three major advantages to
有三个主要优势
an empire all right the first is mass this just means
一个帝国，首先是规模
that they have a lot of people okay they always have an even amount of people
他们有很多人，大家都知道美国人口大约三千五百万
so United States has a population of about 350 million people
美国人口约三千五百万
but remember the United States can also draw on the populations of its allies
美国还可以调动其盟友的人口
which includes the five eyes the Anglosphere but
包括五眼联盟、英联圈；又包括欧洲；又包括东亚、韩国、日本。
also includes Europe it also includes
East Asia South Korea Japan
包括五眼联盟、英联圈；又包括欧洲；又包括东亚、韩国、日本。
basically wherever the Americans have a military base all right
基本上美国在任何有军事基地的地方都能发挥作用
so most of the world are either allies of the United States or vassals United States
因此世界大部分要么是美国的盟友，要么是其附庙国
so the United States can basically draw on in billions and
美国可以从这些地方调动数十亿人
billions of people for its wars okay
数十亿人参与其战争
so it's mass second is the idea of organization
于是它的规模第二点是组织的概念
organization just means a hierarchy of brokers
组织仅仅是指代理层级
and elite that
和精英那
allows you to organize your resources
让你能组织资源
and your people in order to generate wealth
以及人力以产生财富
which is basically scientific technology okay science
它基本上是科学技术，科学与技术
and technology which
以及技术，导致最先进的武器
leads to the most advanced weaponry okay so
于是组织和
think about the United States how they fight this war they have these satellites
想想美国是怎么打这场战争的，他们有这些卫星，能精准打击
that provide for precision targeting
他们还有这些飞机，B‑2轰炸机、F‑15战机…
they have these airplanes these b -2 bombers f -15s
they have these airplanesthese b -2 bombers f -15s
that are the most advanced
那是人类历史上最先进的武器
weaponry ever in human history okay
所以组织和…
so organization and
so organizationand
the last great strength of the Empire
帝国的最后一次伟大力量
is the idea of death death is the idea
是死亡的概念，死亡就是概念
that because your people are infinite
因为你们的人是无穷的
because your organization is so strong because
因为你的组织很强大，因而…
your resources are so
你的资源很…
vast you can afford to lose many many wars
广阔，你可以承受多场战争的失败
okay it's not a big deal the United States loses this
好的，没什么大事，美国在伊朗战役中输了，如果他们想回来……
war in Iran if they want to go back they
他们可以带着更多士兵、更多武器回来……
can go back with even more soldiers even more weaponry
can go back with even moresoldiers even more weaponry
because their wealth is infinite okay
因为他们的财富无限，好的
so these are the three major advantages of an empire
所以这就是帝国的三大优势
and in theory because
而且理论上因为
of these advantages an empire should be
这些优势中，帝国应该是无敌可战、永恒不灭的，但
invincible and eternal but
我们知道的事实是…
we know for a fact that
all empires fall and
所有帝国都会落败，且
they fall very very hard and
它们的崩溃非常猛烈，且
quite honestly they don't last a very long time
说实它们的寿命不算长
maybe 20 years maybe three years for most empires that's not a very long time
也许20年，也许三年，对大多数帝国来说并不算很长的时间
so
于是
we need to better understand what's going on okay why is it
我们需要更好地理解发生了什么事
that an empire with these vast resources they all fall
那种拥有这些庞大资源的帝国最终会在二十年、三十年内落败
in 20 years, 30 years, okay?
二十年、三十年，明白吗
All right, so
好的，接下来我来解释一下
what we need to understand is
我们需要理解的是
that all these advantages are ultimately disadvantages in the long term,
这些优势最终在长期内变成劣势，
all right? So let me explain what I mean.
好的？让我来解释一下我的意思。
Math, you have a lot of people, okay?
数学，你有很多人，明白吗？
When you have a lot of people, you create a lot of inequality.
当你有很多人时，你就会产生很多不平等。
Why? Because there's competition for resources.
为什么？因为资源竞争导致的。
There's too many people, okay?
人太多了，明白吗？
And this often leads to debt and slavery.
并且这常导致债务与奴役。
And as a result, your people become complacent,
于是你的民众便会自满而安。
lazy, indifferent.
懒散，漠然。
They're competing against each other.
他们相互竞争。
They really don't like the government, okay?
他们真的不喜欢政府，明白吗？
So they're not really that motivated to do anything,
于是他们并不真正有动力去做任何事。
to work or to fight wars, but especially to fight wars.
去工作或打仗，但尤其是打仗。
So this math looks like an advantage in the beginning,
所以这算式在开始时看起来像是优势。
but over time, it becomes a disadvantage,
但随着时间推移，它变成了劣势，
all right? Organization means an elite.
对了吧？组织即是精英。
The problem with this is
问题在于
that over time, the elite become parasites.
随着时间推移，精英变成寄生者。
Why? Because the way they make their money is through rent -seeking.
为什么？因为他们赚钱的方式是租金寻求。
Rent -seeking just means that you have power
租金寻求就是指你拥有权力。
and you seek to monetize your power.
并且你想把自己的权力变成金钱。
And you seek to monetize your power by exploiting the mass.
并且你想把自己的权力变成金钱，靠掠夺大众来实现。
All right? So basically,
对了吧？所以基本上，
landlords are a classic type of rent -seeking elite.
地主是典型的租金寻求精英。
And so they don't really work, but
于是他们不真正工作，但……
they make a lot of money because they own the land, because
他们因为拥有土地而赚了很多钱。
they control all the resources, because they control all the capital.
他们掌握所有资源，因为他们掌握所有资本。
And that forces the mass to go into slavery, to go into debt, which is what's happening in America today.
于是大众被迫进入奴役、债务，这正是美国今天的现状。
The problem with this is that everyone wants to be part of the elite.
问题是人人都想成为精英。
And there are too many elite over time, okay?
于是又有太多的精英，行吗？
So even though the elite have many, many kids,
所以即使精英有很多很多孩子，
the power is a zero -sum game.
权力是零和游戏。
It's a hierarchy. And so this leads to the idea of elite overproduction,
它是一个层级结构。于是这导致了精英过度生产的概念，
okay? Elite overproduction.
好吧？精英过度生产。
This is a term coined by the historian Peter Turchin,
这是历史学家彼得·图尔奇恩创造的术语。
okay? And his theory is that
好吧？他的理论是……
you have turmoil, you have wars,
你有动荡，你就有战争，
war, war,
战争，战争
war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war,
战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战,战
war, war,
战，战，
war, war, war, war, war, war, war, war,
战，战，战，战，战，战，战，战，
war okay
战争，好吗
so another saying this is that
于是又有人说这就是
an empire over time becomes insular they don't care about what
一个帝国随着时间变得孤岛化，他们不关心外部世界的事；他们只关心华盛顿的事。
happens outside the world all they care about is what happens in Washington DC
happens outside the world all they careabout is what happens in Washington DC
and
和
as a result they make a lot of stupid mistakes okay
于是他们犯了许多愚蠢的错误，好吗
right the last thing is death okay the problem with death is
好了，最后一件事是死亡，好吗？死亡的问题是
that if there are no consequences to your
如果你的行为没有后果的话
actions you become arrogant you become lazy
行动让你自大、懒惰
and you become incompetent okay
并且你变得无能，好吗
because you don't care it doesn't really matter
因为你不在乎，没什么大不了
let's lease the idea
让我们租个想法
of hubris okay hubris
自大，好自大
is just blindness to your own arrogance of violent arrogance
只是对自己大而已的盲目，才是大而已的盲目
that makes you make silly mistakes
那使你犯愚蠢的错
but you don't recognize your mistakes and
但你却不认识自己的错误并且不断重复同样的错误，直至一辈又一辈，好吗？
you keep on repeating the same mistakes throughout your life over and over again, right?
于是，帝国似乎无敌可战，看来是如此吧？
So yes, it seems like the empire is invincible,
but if you actually think about it,
但如果你真正思考它，
the empire, its advantages becomes over time,
帝国的优势随时间而增大，
its disadvantages, which
它的劣势则随之而增大
will lead ultimately to its downfall, okay?
最终会导致其衰落，好吗？
So the mass leads to inequality,
于是规模导致不平等，
the organization leads to overproduction,
组织导致过度产出，
which leads to factionalism, and death leads to hubris.
导致分裂，死亡则导致自大。
That's why an empire must fall over time.
这就是帝国随时间必然衰落的原因。
But an empire cannot fall by itself.
但帝国本身并不能自衰落。
It needs an enemy that forces it to collapse, okay?
它需要一个敌人来迫使它崩溃，好吗？
And so what happens is that an enemy will emerge
于是发生的事是会出现一个敌人
that will overwhelm the empire
这个敌人将会压倒帝国
because it is able to take advantage of the weaknesses of the empire,
因为它能利用帝国的弱点，
right? And so
对吧？于是
what are the weaknesses of this empire?
这个帝国的弱点是什么？
Well, the first major weakness of this empire is that
好吧，这个帝国的第一个主要弱点是……
the people aren't really motivated.
人们并不真正有动力。
So you, as people, are really motivated, you have a huge advantage, okay?
所以你们，作为人民，真的很有动力，你们有很大的优势，好吗？
We call this energy. All right?
我们把这叫做能量。好吗？
Now, as an empire, you become insular.
现在，作为一个帝国，你变得孤岛化。
You refuse to admit your mistakes.
你拒绝承认自己的错误。
You refuse to learn from others.
你不愿意向他人学习。
Well, if you are willing to admit your mistakes,
好吧，如果你愿意承认自己的错误，
if you're willing to learn,
如果你愿意学习，
if you're willing to promote the best
如果你愿意推广最优秀的
and brightest, if you're willing to be meritocratic, you have a huge advantage, okay?
和最聪明的，若你愿意实行功绩制，你就拥有巨大的优势，好的？
And so this idea of openness.
于是这就是开放性的想法。
Now, the last idea is this.
现在，最后一个想法是这个。
An empire, it's fractured.
一个帝国，它已经分裂。
So if you're able to maintain cohesion,
所以如果你能保持团结，
if people are able to remain united, if they're able to have a common purpose,
如果人们能保持团结，若他们能有共同目标，
they will be strong, okay? So,
他们就会强大，好的？所以，
you know, if an enemy of the empire emerges with these three qualities, energy,
你知道，如果一个帝国的敌人出现并具备这三种特质，能量，
openness, and cohesion, this enemy will defeat the empire.
开放与团结，这个敌人将击败帝国。
It doesn't make sense, okay?
不太通顺，好吗？
So what I want you to focus on as you follow the news in this war between United States
所以我想让你在关注这场美中战争的新闻时聚焦于此。
and Iran is ask yourself a question.
伊朗也请你自己问一个问题。
Will Iran become an energetic, open, and cohesive society?
伊朗会成为一个充满活力、开放且团结的社会吗？
Because if it does, it will become invincible.
如果是，它就会变得无敌可战。
The empire won't change because of hubris.
帝国因自负而不变。
It's too static.
它太静止。
It's too stagnant, too bureaucratic.
它太停滞，太官僚。
So the empire won't change.
于是帝国不变。
The empire will not admit its own mistakes.
帝国不会承认自己的错误。
And quite honestly, Iran,
而且，伊朗，
because it's still a country of 92 million people,
因为它仍是一个9200万人的国家，
it still suffers from issues of mass organization and death.
它仍然面临大规模组织与死亡问题，
And so if it's able to transform itself into an energetic,
于是若它能把自己转变为充沛的国家，
open, and cohesive society, then it will be invincible.
开放且团结的社会，便会无敌可战。
It will triumph over America.
它将战胜美国。
That is the fundamental question in this war, okay?
这就是这场战争的根本问题，行吗？
Don't worry about America, its technology.
别担心美国的技术。
Don't worry about the economy.
别担心经济。
Don't worry about these things, okay?
别担心这些事，行吗？
Just ask yourself one question.
只需问自己一个问题。
Is Iran transforming as a society?
伊朗正以社会的方式转型吗？
Are people becoming much more motivated?
人们的积极性是否大幅提升？
Are people in Iran learning from their mistakes?
伊朗人们在从错误中学习吗？
And innovating and becoming resilient on the battlefield?
并在战场上创新并变得更有韧性吗？
Are the Iranians sticking together as a people?
伊朗人们作为一个民族团结在一起吗？
Okay? Because if the answer is yes to all three questions,
好的？因为如果对这三个问题都回答是，伊朗就会赢，美方就会输。好的？这样说对吗？没问题。
then Iran will win and America will lose.
Okay? Does that make sense? All right.
好的？因为如果对这三个问题都回答是，伊朗就会赢，美方就会输。好的？这样说对吗？没问题。
So that's just a theory. So
于是这只是个理论。于是
let's now talk
接下来我们来聊聊
specifically about America and Iran, okay?
具体说说美国和伊朗，好吗？
So America will have three
于是美国在这场战争中将拥有三大优势，好的？
major advantages in this war, okay?
这三大优势当然是，
These three advantages are, of course,
technology, propaganda,
技术，宣传，
and
和
money, wealth.
金钱，财富。
These are the three major strengths of the American empire.
这些是美国帝国的三大优势。
All right? Technology is just what you see every day, right?
好的？技术就是你每天看到的东西，对吧？
The satellites that are able to position,
能够定位的卫星，
target these airplanes
目标这些飞机
that are the greatest war machines in the world.
它们是世界上最强大的战争机器。
Okay? So America is home to the greatest scientists,
好吧？所以美国是最伟大科学家的家园。
the most advanced weaponry, okay?
最先进的武器，明白吗？
That's just technology. Propaganda means
这只是技术。宣传就是…
that America controls information space.
美国掌控信息空间。
It controls the internet.
它掌控互联网。
It controls the world's most powerful media,
它掌控全球最强大的媒体，
including the New York Times, CNN,
包括《纽约时报》、CNN、
BBC. It controls YouTube.
BBC。它掌控YouTube。
It controls Google. It controls information landscape.
它掌控Google。它掌控信息景观。
America does not want you to know something.
美国不想让你知道这件事。
It can hide it from you. America can control the discourse.
它可以把它隐藏在你面前。美国可以掌控话语。
It can control how you think about the world.
它能决定你对世界的看法。
That's propaganda. The last thing is money, okay?
那是宣传。最后一件事是钱，行吗？
And it's a very simple idea. The United States controls the US dollar,
美国掌控美元，
which is the reserve currency of the world. And
它是世界的储备货币。
the United States can print as much US
美国可以按需印制足够的美元，以赢得这场战争。
dollars as it needs in order to win this war.
It has an infinite money printer.
它有一台无限印钞机。
Okay? And then
好了？然后呢？
it can use this money to
它可以用这笔钱来
bribe people to fight this war.
贿赂人们去打这场战争。
It can pay for mercenaries.
它可以支付雇佣兵。
It can bribe ethnic minorities to rebel against the government.
它可以贿赂少数民族反叛政府。
It can bribe Iranian officials to betray the government.
它可以贿赂伊朗官员背叛政府。
Okay? So,
好了？
looking at these three things, you would think that America is invisible.
看着这三件事，你会觉得美国无形。
Right? But again,
对吧？但再说一次，
we need to think about the law's asymmetry
我们还得思考这条法则的非对称性。
and recognize that these advantages are also disadvantages.
并且认识到这些优势也是劣势。
All right? So, let's discuss this.
好的？那我们来讨论一下。
Technology. Well, you know,
技术。嗯，你知道的。
if you have those advanced weaponry, in the world,
如果你拥有世界上最先进的武器，
you become lazy,
你会变得懒散，
arrogant, and dependent on the technology.
自负自傲并依赖技术。
Right? So, the classic example, of course, is our school
对吧？那么，经典例子当然是我们的学校。
where you have access to chat GPT.
在那里你可以使用 ChatGPT。
Right? And like, you become smarter because you have access to chat GPT.
对吧？于是你因为使用ChatGPT 而变得更聪明。
No, you become dumber because you become lazy.
不，你会变得更笨，因为你变懒了。
Right? Same with technology.
对吧？技术也是一样。
You would think that with the most advanced weaponry in the world,
你会以为世界上最先进的武器而自以为傲。
America would become invincible.
美国将变得无敌可战。
But instead, people become,
但相反，人民变成了……
the American military becomes too dependent on the technology.
美军对技术的依赖过重。
It becomes too arrogant, too complacent.
它变得太自大，太自满。
Okay? It's like, well, you know, if we're in trouble,
好了？就像，嗯，你知道，如果我们遇到麻烦，
then we'll just send in the Air Force.
那我们就直接派空军来。
And we'll have enough. Okay? So, it leads to dependency.
我们会有足够的。好了？于是就形成了依赖。
And this actually hampers innovation
这实际上阻碍了创新
and resilience in the battlefield.
并且在战场上造成了韧性不足。
And this is what you need to win. Okay?
这就是你赢得胜利所需的。好吗？
You need to be innovative and you need to be resilient on the battlefield.
你需要在战场上具备创新与韧性。
But because of technology, you become too lazy
但因技术，便会变得懒散。
to think for yourself. All right?
自己思考。好吗？
So, that's one problem. Propaganda.
所以，这就是一个问题。宣传。
You would think that, oh, America controls the debate.
你会想，哦，美国掌控了辩论。
Therefore, that's a huge advantage.
因此，这就是一个巨大的优势。
It's actually not an advantage,
其实这并不是优势，
guys. The reason why is that, in order for innovation
伙计们。原因在于，为了创新
and resilience to happen, you need to have open debate.
并且韧性得以发生，你需要有开放的辩论。
Right? You need people to voice dissenting opinions.
对吧？你需要人们发声异议。
But if you control the information landscape,
但若你掌控信息景观，
what you can do is censor.
你可以做的就是进行审查。
And that's what America's doing right now.
这正是美国现在正在做的事。
It's telling people to shut up and obey.
它让人们闭嘴服从。
You're not allowed to point out that this war is stupid
你们不能说这场战争是愚蠢的，美国也赢不了这场战争。
and America can't win this war.
否则就会被踢出去。
Otherwise, you'll be kicked out.
Okay? So,
好的？所以，
this means that
这意味着
there's really a lack of rigorous debate within the American government,
美国政府内部确实缺乏严谨的辩论。
within the American military, within the American elite,
在美国军队内部，在美国精英内部，
which, of course, will lead to hubris.
这当然会导致自负。
It will lead to bad decision making.
这将导致决策失误。
No one will point this out because they're too afraid of pissing off
没人会指出这一点，因为他们怕惹到总统和他的团队。
the president and his people.
于是他们闭嘴，结果美国又一次又一次犯同样的错。
So, they'll shut up and America will keep on making the same mistakes over and over again.
So, they'll shut up and America will keep onmaking the same mistakes over and over again.
Okay? We call this the Okay?
好的？我们把它叫做“好的”？
They're basically getting high on their own supply is another phrase that we use.
他们基本上是靠自己的供应高兴，另外一句我们也用来形容。
All right. Money and wealth.
好的。钱和财富。
You think, okay, well, this is it, man.
你想，好的，嗯，就是这样，兄弟。
We just bribe everyone. We just bribe the entire world and
我们只要贿赂所有人。我们只要贿赂全世界，然后就好了。
we're good.
我们就好了。
Right? The problem is this.
对吧？问题在于。
The problem is that if you bribe people,
问题是如果你贿赂人，
they're not going to fight for you. Right?
他们就不会为你而战。
Because all they want is your money.
因为他们只想要你的钱。
So, you bribe them, but they'll probably take your money and run away.
于是你贿赂他们，但他们很可能把钱拿走后逃跑。
Okay? Or they'll figure out how to get more money out of you by cheating you.
或者他们会想办法再骗你取更多钱。
So, right now, the Americans are going to fund these militias
于是，现在美国要资助这些民兵、少数民族和反对手对伊朗。
and ethnic minorities and opposition groups against Iran.
好吗？猜猜看，伙计们？
Okay? Guess what, guys?
These guys are hustlers. Right?
这些人是个贼人。对吧？
They're not fighting because they want more freedom.
他们不是为了自由而战斗。
They're fighting because they want to rip off the US government.
他们战斗是为了抢美国政府的钱。
And so, this money issue can be a problem in the long term
于是，这笔钱的问题在长期里可能会出现。
because the people you're bribing, you can't even trust.
因为你要贿赂的人，你根本就不可信。
And they're not motivated to actually win this war for you.
他们也并非为了帮你赢得这场战争而努力。
They're actually motivated to scam you as much as possible.
他们实际上会尽可能多地骗你。
And they could be actually a problem in the long term because
而且这在长期里可能成为问题，因为
you're putting so much resources into these hustlers.
你把这么多资源投入到这些贼人身上。
Okay? All right.
好的？没问题。
So, what this means is
所以，这意味着是
that America has three major problems.
美国有三个主要问题。
Okay? It has three major problems.
好的？它有三个主要问题。
The first major problem is the lack of political will.
第一个主要问题是政治意愿的缺乏。
And all this is saying is that
而这一切都说明的是
the American people don't want to fight this war.
美国人民不想打这场战争。
The American government, doesn't even know why they're fighting this war.
美国政府甚至不知道自己为什么打这场战争。
No one cares. Okay?
谁也不在乎。
But for the Iranians,
但对伊朗人来说，
it's a struggle of life and death.
这是一场生死之争。
Right? If America loses this war, they just go home and forget about it.
对吧？如果美国赢了这场战争，他们就回家忘了它。
But if the Iranians lose this war, they all get killed.
但若伊朗人输掉这场战争，他们就全被杀死。
Or they lose their country, they lose their society, they lose their civilization,
或者他们失去国家、社会、文明，
they lose their identity. They cannot afford to lose this war.
失去身份。他们不能再输这场战争。
Okay? So, the first major problem that Americans are facing is,
好的？那么，美国人面临的第一个主要问题是，
they don't have any political will to fight this war, but they're still fighting this war anyway.
他们没有任何政治意愿去打这场战争，但仍然在打。
Okay? The question then, of course, is why?
好吧？于是问题自然是，为什么会这样？
Why is this happening? This is actually the most important question, and it's the most complicated.
为什么会这样？这才是最重要的问题，也是最复杂的。
So, we'll save this for later.
所以，我们先留到后面来。
Okay? Second is the idea of logistics
好吧？第二个是后勤的概念。
and manufacturing.
和制造。
So, America is very good at fighting short wars.
所以，美国在短期战争中非常擅长。
Okay? The reason why is, they're advanced,
好吧？原因是它们很先进，
they have the most advanced weaponry, but they have manufacturing issues.
他们拥有最先进的武器，但制造方面有问题。
Because, as we know,
因为，正如我们所知，
America ships all its factories to China.
美国把所有工厂运往中国。
So, America doesn't have that many factories.
所以，美国没有那么多的工厂。
So, yes, it has the most advanced weaponry in the world, but
所以，是的，它拥有世界上最先进的武器，但……
this weapon doesn't do any good if you don't have any munitions.
如果没有弹药，这种武器也没什么用。
Right? If you don't have any munitions, bombs, bullets.
对吧？如果没有弹药、炸弹、子弹。
And you need factories for that.
你需要工厂来生产。
America doesn't really have these factories.
美国确实没有这些工厂。
Now, I understand that America is trying to
现在，我明白美国正试图提升其制造能力，
upgrade its manufacturing capacity,
但进展有点慢。
but it's kind of slow.
but it's kind ofslow.
So maybe five years from now, it will have manufacturing capacity to fight this war,
也许在五年后，它将拥有足够的制造能力来打这场战争，但现在还没有。
but right now it doesn't. So
这又是另一个主要问题，好的？
that's another major issue, okay?
And then the last issue, of course, is casualties.
然后最后一个问题，当然是伤亡。
Specialties. All right,
专业化。好了，
America, because it doesn't have the political will to fight this war,
美国，因为它没有政治意愿去打这场战争。
cannot afford to lose soldiers on the battlefield.
不能在战场上失去士兵。
All right? So
好了？所以
it wants to minimize the death,
它想减少死亡。
it wants to minimize battlefield losses, because
它想在战场上减少损失，因为
if like a thousand,
如果像一千人，
tens of thousands of American soldiers are going home to America dead in coffins,
数万美军士兵回国时装在棺材里
I guarantee you,
我向你保证，
because of lack of political will, the American people will revolt.
因为缺乏政治意志，美国人民会起义。
You have protests, you will have a lot of violence in the streets.
你会有示威，街头会有大乱。
It'll be like the Vietnam era again.
就像越战时期一样。
All right? Okay, so,
好的？那好，
yes, I understand that America has technology, propaganda,
是的，我知道美国有技术、宣传，
and money, but as we discussed, these aren't really advantages.
和钱，但正如我们讨论的那样，这些并不是真正的优势。
And these disadvantages are huge.
这些劣势则非常巨大。
The lack of political will, the lack of manufacturing,
缺乏政治意志，缺乏制造力。
and the lack of,
和缺乏，
America cannot afford to lose that many soldiers in the battlefield, okay? And so,
美国不能在战场上失去那么多士兵，好的？于是，
this situation now determines how America will fight this war.
此情形现在决定美国将如何作战。
And we'll discuss this later on, okay?
好的，稍后再讨论。
All right, now let's talk about Iran.
好的，现在来聊聊伊朗。
Okay, so, the United States is a very, very, very, very, very, very,
好的，接着说，美国是个非常非常非常非常非常非常…
very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very,
非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，
very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very,
非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，
very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very, very,
非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，非常，
very, very,
非常，非常，
very, of
非常，
eschatology, of individual sacrifice for the greater good.
末世论，个人牺牲为大义。
The Shia are not afraid to die.
什叶派不怕死。
And because their great religious leader,
并且因为他们伟大的宗教领袖，
the Ayatollah Khomeini was assassinated by the Americans and Israelis,
阿亚图拉·霍梅尼被美以色两国暗杀。
they are motivated to seek vengeance,
他们有寻仇的动机
to martyr themselves for the greater good,
为更大善牺牲自己
to seek eternal paradise, okay, jihad.
去寻永生之乐，好的，圣战。
All right, that's the first major advantage.
好的，这就是第一个主要优势。
The second major advantage is terrain.
第二个主要优势是地形。
And all this means is that
而这一切都意味着是……
Iran is a mountainous country.
伊朗是个山地国家。
And it's huge, it's three times the size of Iraq.
它又很大，面积是伊拉克的三倍。
So it's very hard for America to invade the country.
因此美国入侵伊朗非常困难。
In fact, most analysts will say,
事实上，大多数分析师会说，
will tell you, it is suicidal for the American military to invade Iran.
会告诉你，入侵伊朗对美军来说是自杀的事，
It is a mountain fortress, okay, it's a fortress.
它是山地堡垒，好的，就是堡垒。
And the last issue is,
还有最后一个问题，
the last advantage is nationalism.
最后一个优势是民族主义。
Okay. All right.
好的，全部完成。
So the Iranians are Persians.
伊朗人是波斯人。
And the Persians go back 5,000 years.
波斯人有五千年的历史。
It is one of the greatest civilizations in human history.
它是人类历史上最伟大的文明之一。
And as we discussed last semester, in the ancient world, there were three great civilizations,
正如上学期所说，古代有三大文明，
right, the Jews, the Greeks, and the Persians.
对，犹太人、希腊人和波斯人。
And the Persian culture, it's vast, it's beautiful,
波斯文化广阔而美丽。
and it's deep, and
并且很深厚，且
that's what gives the Iranian people a lot of pride,
这就是伊朗人自豪的原因，
okay? So, when they're fighting,
好吧？所以他们打仗时，
they're not just fighting for their religion, they're not just fighting for their homes,
他们不只是为宗教而战，也不只是为家园而战，
they're fighting for their entire civilization
他们为整个文明而战
that goes back 5,000 years.
这文明可追溯五千年前
Right, so these are the three major advantages
好的，下面是伊朗人拥有的三大优势
that the Iranians have, okay?
那就是伊朗人的三大优势，明白了吗？
Faith means that they're not afraid to die
信仰意味着他们不怕牺
for what they believe in.
为他们所信仰的事物。
Terrain means that the Americans will have a hard problem invading the country.
地形意味着美国人入侵该国时会遇到大难。
Nationalism means that the people will be able to live, they will all be reigned, know what they're fighting for.
民族主义让人民能自足，统一，明白自己在为之而战。
Alright? So, but again, remember,
好的？那好，记住，
everything that seems like an advantage can be a disadvantage as well, alright?
所有看似优势的事也可能是劣势，好吗？
So, let's go over what the problems are.
好了，先说说问题在哪。
With faith, you might have an issue of blindness,
凭信念，你可能会出现盲目之症，
okay? Or zealotry.
好吗？或者是狂热。
Where you're not afraid to die,
你不怕死的那一刻。
but that means that
但那就意味着……
you're not thinking strategically, okay?
你没有在思考战略，好吗？
Maybe you're gonna waste too many soldiers on the battlefield.
你可能会在战场上浪费太多兵力。
They're brave, but they're kind of stupid as well.
他们很勇敢，但也有点傻气。
Alright, so you might have an issue
好了，可能会出现……
where Iran is not using the optimal strategy
伊朗没有采用最优策略。
because their soldiers are not afraid of death.
因为他们的士兵不怕死亡。
And we're already seeing that where
而我们已经看到的情况是……
the Americans have already blown up and destroyed the Iranian navy.
美国已经炸毁并摧毁了伊朗海军。
Now, any of you guys know that, right? I'm not saying that you're not afraid,
现在，你们中有人知道这件事吧？我不是说你们不怕，
the first thing the Americans would do is go destroy the Iranian navy,
美国首先会去摧毁伊朗海军，
so you should probably not use the navy, or hide the navy, or blow up the navy yourself,
所以你们最好不要用海军，或者把海军隐藏起来，或者自己炸掉海军。
okay? Because you want to avoid as many casualties as possible,
好的？因为你想尽量避免伤亡，
but they didn't do that, and the Americans have now destroyed the Iranian navy,
但他们没这么做，结果美国又摧毁了伊朗海军，
alright? So, that's the issue of faith.
好了？这就是信念的问题。
Terrain, yeah, it's a fortress,
地形，嗯，是一座堡垒，
but it can also be a prison, right?
它也可以是个牢房，没错吗？
Where you're just sort of stuck there, and because
你就那样被卡住了，
it's a mountainous region, it doesn't have that many resources,
它是个山地地区，资源不多，
so Americans can actually disrupt your water supply,
美国人可以切断你的水源，
disrupt your electricity, okay, and cause general poverty
切断电力，造成普遍贫困
and hardship for your people, okay?
和你们人民的艰辛，没错吗？
And then nationalism,
然后是民族主义，
yes, Persia is a great culture, but
是的，波斯是伟大的文化，但
remember that Iran is an ethnically diverse country.
记住伊朗是个民族多样的国家。
In fact, only 50% of the population of Iran in the Terrain are Persians.
实际上，伊朗人口中只有50%是波斯人。
Others are different minorities, okay?
其余者是各类少数民族，明白吗？
Alright? So, you have
好的？那么，你有…
then ethnic divisions, right?
然后是民族分裂，对吗？
Okay? So, looking at this,
好的？看着这个…
now we know exactly what the American strategy will be.
现在我们已经完全知道美国的战略是什么了。
Basically, the strategy will be
基本上，这个战略就是……
to inflict as many casualties as possible on the Iranians,
对伊朗人造成尽可能多的伤亡。
alright?
好的？
To kill as many people as possible, destroy the infrastructure of Iran
杀尽可能多的人，摧毁伊朗的基础设施，令人民缺水缺电缺粮，才能生存，好吗？
so that the people don't have enough water, electricity, food to survive, okay?
好吧？
And the third, of course,
第三点当然是
is to create as much ethnic tension in the country as possible by arming
在国内通过武装和鼓动来制造尽可能多的民族紧张。
and encouraging and
and encouragingand
bribing ethnic groups to rebel against the central government in Terrain,
给各族群贿赂，让他们在领土上反叛中央政府
alright? Okay?
好吧？
But again,
再说一次，
what the law of symmetry, asymmetry tells us is
什么是对称律与非对称律告诉我们的
that the empire ultimately is not as flexible
帝国最终并不像其敌人那样灵活
and open and dynamic as its enemy,
并且开放且动态
okay?
好吧？
The weaker person is going to engage in much more self -reflection,
弱者将会进行更多的自省思考，
self -debate than the empire,
自我辩论
okay? Because the empire will become arrogant.
好吧？因为帝国会变得自负。
And so ultimately,
于是，最终，
Iran should triumph over America.
伊朗应当战胜美国。
And in fact, what's going to happen is that
而且，实际上会发生的事是
this strategy that America will use
美国将会使用的这套策略
against the Iranians will lead to the Iranians becoming much more energetic,
对伊朗人来说会使他们更为活跃
open, and cohesive,
打开，并连贯，
okay?
好吧？
So, let's look at the American strategy specifically.
于是，让我们具体看看美国的策略。
And, anyway, we're gonna deal with that shortly.
好吧，我们很快会处理这个。
we're gonna deal with that shortly. And, anyway, we're gonna deal with that shortly.
我们很快会处理这个。好吧，我们很快会处理这个。
And, anyway, And, anyway, we're gonna deal with that shortly.
好吧，好吧，我们很快会处理这个。
And, anyway, we're gonna deal with that shortly. And, anyway, And, anyway, we're gonna deal with that shortly.
好吧，我们很快会处理这个。好吧，好吧，我们很快会处理这个。
And, anyway, we're gonna deal with that shortly.
好吧，我们很快会处理这个。
好吧，反正，咱们很快会处理这个。
And, anyway,
好吧，反正，
and the Baliks.
以及巴利克人。
Okay? These are the three major problem areas for Iran,
好的？这就是伊朗的三大问题区。
and it's always been the case.
而且这一直是事实。
Remember, the Persians are in the middle.
记住，波斯人处于中间。
So, the Baliks are, first of all,
于是，巴利克人首先是，
Sunni Muslims.
逊尼穆斯林。
As we discussed last class, the Sunnis and
正如上节所说，逊尼人和
the Shias have never really gotten along well together.
什叶派从来就不太能和睦邻相处。
They have different, I mean, the same religion, Islam,
他们有同宗教，伊斯兰，差别在信仰体系。
but they have different belief systems.
但信仰体系各不相同。
That's led to a lot of conflicts in the past.
这导致了过去的许多冲突。
It's almost like the Catholics and the Protestants, okay?
就像天主教和新教一样，行吗？
And so, the Baliks have been trying to rebel against Iranians for a long time.
于是，巴利克人长期试图反抗伊朗。
I guarantee you that there are already Israeli
我向你保证，已经有以色列人和美军特种部队驻扎在此地，行吗？
and American special forces embedded in this area, okay?
原因是……
The reason why is that
they want to encourage as much civil conflict as possible,
他们想尽可能多地制造内战，但也想为地面入侵美国做准备。
but they also want to prepare the possibility for a ground invasion of America.
好吧？所以，】
Okay? So,
they would need a forward operating base, and
他们需要一个前进作战基地，而这片地区可以成为陆权入侵的起点。
this area could be a very good place for a beginning of a land invasion.
然后你来到这里，你会遇到库尔德人。
Then you over here, you have the Kurds.
Then you over here,you have the Kurds.
Okay? The Kurds are another minority that
好的？库尔德人是另一支寻求民族主权的少数民族。
seeks national sovereignty.
现在，正在发生的事是…
And right now, what's happening is
that the Americans and Israelis are bombing this area heavily,
美国和以色列人正在猛烈轰炸这片地区，
and they're targeting police stations.
他们正瞄准警察局。
Why? Because they're trying to reduce and
为什么？因为他们想要减少…
eliminate opposition so that
消除对手，以便
they can arm the Kurds and have them come into this area
他们可以给库尔德人武装，让他们进入此区
and threaten Iran.
并威胁伊朗。
What's also happening is that in Iraq,
在伊拉克也在发生同样的事，
there are these Sunni groups,
有这些逊尼团体，
okay, that the Americans are basically bribing
美国基本上在贿赐
and arming, and they're basically fanatics.
并且武装，基本是狂热分子。
Okay? They're ISIS. And
好？他们是ISIS。还有
what the Americans want to do is send
美国想做的事是派
them into Iran to cause as much problems as possible.
把他们送到伊朗，制造尽可能多的问题。
Okay? Then you over here, you have Azerbaijan.
好？然后你在这里，你有阿塞拜疆。
Azerbaijan, it is an independent country.
阿塞拜疆，它是一个独立的国家。
What's really odd is that
真正奇怪的是
the majority of ethnic Azeris are actually in Iran.
大多数阿塞拜疆族人实际上在伊朗。
Six percent are in the country.
六个百分点在阿塞拜疆国。
Forty percent are...
四十％在……
Forty percent are in the country of Azerbaijan, which means that
四十％在阿塞拜疆国，这意味着……
from the perspective of the Azerbaijani people,
从阿塞拜疆人的角度来看……
this war could be an
这场战争可能是一个机会，
opportunity to reunite the people,
可以让人们团聚，
okay, and create a greater Azerbaijan.
好，形成更大的阿塞拜疆。
So these are the three problem areas
于是这三大问题区间……
that you have to watch as this war develops over the next few weeks,
你需要在接下来几周内跟踪……
over the next few months. Okay?
以及接下来几个月内观察……
So, we already know what's happening.
于是，我们已经知道发生了什么。
We already know what the American strategy will be because we've seen it in Libya,
我们已经知道美国的策略是什么，因为我们已经在利比亚看到过。
in Syria before.
我们已经知道美国的策略是什么，因为我们已经在叙利亚看到过。
Okay, so what is the strategy?
好的，那策略是什么？
Right. So, again,
对，回到起点。
the strategy is to both attack without,
策略是从外部同时发动攻击，
okay, from outside, and inside as well.
好的，从外部也从内部同时进行。
So, what you're going to do is this.
于是，你接下来要做的事就是这样。
You're going to arm these people,
你要给这些人配备武器。
embed special forces into these insurgent groups to lead them.
嵌入特种部队到这些叛军团中，领其作战。
You're going to attack them and provide air cover so
你将攻击他们并提供空中掩护。
they have a clear path into Iran and are able to limit opposition, okay?
他们有一条清晰的路线进入伊朗，并能限制反对手，好吗？
All right? So, now you're attacking from without.
好了，现在你从外部发动攻击。
With attacking from within means to cause as much pain
从内部发动攻击意味着造成尽可能多的痛苦
and suffering in the interior
以及内部的苦难
of Iran as possible. All right?
伊朗的可能性。好吗？
And how do you do that? Well, you do that through decapitation.
然后你怎么做？好吧，你通过去头部来做。
Okay, let's go over the strategies.
好了，接下来我们来回顾一下策略。
Okay. Decapitation.
好的。去头部。
Okay. And
好的。还有
what you're doing is you're removing the elite,
你正在做的就是去掉精英。
okay, or what we call command and control.
好的，或者我们称之为指挥控制。
Okay? You're basically limiting the capacity of Iran to govern itself,
好的？你基本上限制了伊朗自我治理的能力，拥有领导层，拥有精英。
to have a leadership, to have an elite. All right?
好了，全部就这样。
Command and control. Okay? So, that's the first strategy.
指挥控制。好吧？这就是第一个策略。
Second strategy. Okay.
第二个策略。好。
And the third strategy is aerial bombardment, okay?
第三个策略是空中轰炸，好吧？
Aerial supremacy. So,
空中霸权。于是，
again, America has the most advanced airplanes in the world.
再说一次，美国拥有世界上最先进的飞机。
And the way that
而且方式是
it's using its airplanes is to destroy as much military installation as possible,
它使用飞机的目的是尽可能摧毁军事设施，
but it's also engaging in acts of sabotage.
它还在进行破坏行动。
Okay? So, what they're doing is they're carpet bombing.
他们正在进行地毯轰炸。
Okay? So, they're carpet bombing Tehran.
好的？于是，他们在对德黑兰进行地毯轰炸。
Okay? They're doing soft targeting.
好的？他们在进行软目标打击。
Soft targeting. Soft targeting means that instead of attacking military installations, you attack hospitals.
软目标打击是指不是攻击军事设施，而是攻击医院。
Why? Because
为什么？因为
you're degrading the capacity to rejuvenate itself,
你正在削弱自身的再生能力，
to be resilient. Okay? Now, the last thing is something called double tap.
以便更具韧性。好了？最后一件事叫双击。
Double tap is this. Okay?
双击就是这样。好吗？
And it's really illegal or against international law.
它真的很不合法，或者说是违反国际法的。
What you do is this. You attack a place.
你所做的就是这样。你先攻击一个地方。
Right? You kill some people. And then people try to come
对吧？你先杀几个人。然后人们会去赶来救伤者。
and help the people who are injured.
他们可能就是医生。
And they could be like doctors.
It could be emergency personnel.
它可能是急救人员。
It could be relatives. Right? And then
它可能是亲属。对吧？然后
you strike again to create as many civilian casualties as possible.
你再打一次，制造尽可能多的平民伤亡。
Okay? And the entire idea is to create as much fear
好的？整个想法就是制造尽可能多的恐惧与焦虑
and anxiety in people as possible
让人们失去抵抗的能力。
so that they lose the capacity to resist.
And the last thing you do...
然后你做的最后一件事……
And the last thing, of course,
最后一件事，当然是……
is to arm
就是武装
and bribe insurgents.
并贿赂叛军。
Okay? So, these are the three main pillars of the American strategy.
好吧？所以，这就是美国战略的三大支柱。
And you will see this over the next few weeks.
接下来几周你会看到这一点。
The problem with this is
问题在于……
that when you do these three things,
当你做这三件事时，
you're not actually hurting the Iranians.
你并没有真正伤害伊朗人。
You're actually helping them.
你实际上在帮他们。
Because remember, the law of asymmetry states
因为记得，非对称法则说……
that whichever group is able to create energy,
……只要哪一方能创造能量，
openness, and cohesion will win.
开放与凝聚将获胜。
And guess what, guys? This American strategy is going to create a more powerful
猜猜怎么了，伙计们？这美国策略将造就更强大的……
and more powerful group. A more energetic, more open, and
更有活力、更开放、更有活力的……
more cohesive Persian society.
更具凝聚力的波斯社会。
All right? Let me show you how.
好的？让我来演示。
All right. Decapitation.
好的。去头术。
We just said that one major problem for America is elite overproduction.
我们刚才说过，美国的一个主要问题是精英过剩。
Right? Well, with decapitation,
对吧？好吧，去头术之后，
what you're doing is you're
你正在做的就是你……
solving this problem for the Iranians.
解决了伊朗人的这个问题。
Right? Before, the huge problem for the Iranians were you have too many leaders, too many leaders And now, you're doing this to the Iranians.
之前，伊朗人的大问题是领导层过多，过多，过多。现在，你正在为伊朗人做这件事。
And they all have their own stupid opinion and they all want to lead this war.
他们都有自己的傻瓜想法，都想带领这场战争。
Right? But by killing so many leaders,
对吧？但杀掉这么多领导人，
you allow for more mobility,
你就让他们更灵活，
for more meritocracy.
更能体现才干的制度。
Right? You're solving the problem of elite overproduction for the Iranians.
对吧？你正在解决伊朗人精英过剩的问题。
That's a huge, huge bonus, guys.
这可是一个巨大的、巨大的加分，伙计们。
Okay? So,
好吧？
the leadership will become much more lean,
领导层将变得更精简，
much more mean, much more determined, and much more strategic.
更有决断力，更有决意，且更具战略性。
Okay? That's number one.
好的？这就是第一点。
Number two, Arab supremacy.
第二点，阿拉伯霸权。
Well, when you do this to people, you cover bomb Tehran,
好吧，当你把这件事做给人们时，覆盖德黑兰的炸弹，
you're creating a more cohesive society.
你就能创造一个更团结的社会。
Why? Because
为什么？因为
the major conflict in Iran for many decades was the conflict between the urban areas
多年来伊朗的主要冲突是城市地区与乡村地区之间的冲突。
and the rural areas. The rural areas were very religious,
乡村地区非常宗教化。
very poor, very backward.
非常贫穷，十分落后。
And the urban areas were educated,
而城市地区则受过教育，世俗化，且…
secular, and...
Right? They were very progressive. Okay?
对吗？他们很进步。好了？
And so, there's this huge conflict that led to a lot of riots,
于是，出现了这场大冲突，导致伊朗发生了大量骚乱，
a lot of protests in Iran.
随后出现了大量示威。
But when you cover bomb the cities,
但当你轰炸城市时，
which are the main source of support for progressive Western policies,
它们是支持进步西方政策的主要来源，
you make them united with the rural areas.
你把他们与农村地区团结起来。
Okay? Does that make sense?
好了？这样说通吗？
The Iranian people no longer see themselves, each other, as enemies.
伊朗人民不再把彼此视为敌人。
They see the Americans, the Israelis, as enemies.
他们把美国人、以色列人视为敌人。
You create a much more cohesive society.
你创造了更为凝聚的社会。
Which are...
它们是……
Who are willing to fight together.
谁愿意一起作战
And that's a problem.
这就是问题所在
Okay? All right.
好的？没问题。
The last thing. Yes, you are arming the assertions,
最后一件事。是的，你正在装备主张。
the Bullocks, the Kurds, the Israelis.
布尔克人、库尔德人、以色列人。
Okay? That's fine. The problem with this is
好？没问题。这个的难点在于
that you are now activating,
你现在正把它们激活，
galvanizing Persian nationalism.
激发波斯民族主义。
Right? For the longest time, you've been doing this.
对吗？你已经做了很久。
For the longest time, the Persian national identity was suppressed by the theocracy.
在很长一段时间里，波斯民族身份被神权统治压抑。
Because they want to create a more...
因为他们想创造一个更…
They want to create a grand religion that unites all ethnicities.
他们想创造一个统一所有民族的伟大宗教。
When you turn the other minorities against the Iranians,
当你把其他少数民族拉到伊朗人对立时，
then the Persian people have to come together and
然后波斯人要聚在一起，记住自己的历史，庆祝自己的身份。
remember their history, celebrate their identity.
这才是关键。好吗？
And this is the key. Okay?
And this is thekey. Okay?
Once the Persian people are able to activate their long -lost memories,
一旦波斯人能够激活久失的记忆，
go back in the past and remember their greatness,
回溯过去，记住他们的伟大，
they come together as an energetic, open, and cohesive society.
便会聚成一支活力十足、开放且团结的社会。
So, yes, the Americans have this strategy
所以，没错，美国人确实有这个策略
that worked in Libya and Syria and other places, but it's not going to work in Iran.
那在利比亚、叙利亚等地奏效，但在伊朗却不会奏效。
In fact, it's going to do the opposite in Iran.
实际上，它在伊朗会做相反的事。
Okay? And then you're like, well,
好吧？然后你会说，嗯，
why don't the Americans not do this?
美国人为什么不这么做呢？
And I already told you, because it is an empire, okay?
我已经告诉你了，因为它是一个帝国，明白吗？
It doesn't care about Iran, it cares about itself.
它不关心伊朗，关心的是自己。
And so, it's sort of stuck with this policy, because, remember,
于是它就被这套政策卡住了，记得吗，
it's trying to win this war as quickly as possible,
它正努力尽快赢得这场战争。
because it doesn't have the manufactured capacity to fight this war for a long time.
因为它没有制造能力能持续作战
It's trying to reduce as many civilian casualties, sorry,
它正努力减少尽可能多的平民伤亡
it's trying to reduce as many casualties among its soldiers as possible,
它正努力尽可能减少士兵伤亡
because the Americans don't want to fight this war, they don't have the political will to fight this war.
因为美国人不想打这场战争，缺乏政治意愿
Americans are trying to win this war cheaply and fast.
美国人正试图以低成本、快速赢得这场战争。
If it doesn't, then Americans are in a lot of trouble.
如果不行，美国人就会陷入大麻烦。
Okay? Does that make sense, guys? All right.
好的？这样说通吗，大家？好的。
Let me now conclude,
现在让我来总结一下，
oh, sorry, let me now discuss the Iranian strategy, okay?
哦，抱歉，让我现在来讨论伊朗的策略，好吗？
So, what the Americans are using is a classic strategy called siege warfare.
于是美国人采用的就是经典的围攻战术。
Okay? Okay? Okay?
好？好？好？
And so, what the Iranians are going to do is they're going to respond with a classic strategy called guerrilla warfare.
于是伊朗人将采取的就是经典的游击战术。
Okay? And guerrilla warfare, guys, it's this simple, it's hide and seek.
好？游击战术，大家，就是这么简单，藏身与寻找。
All right? So, you come bomb me with all, everything you have, I'll just hide in my mountains.
好的？所以，你们用全力轰炸我，我就藏在山里。
And then when you leave, what am I going to do?
然后你们离开，我又该怎么办？
I'm going to attack your GCC countries.
我要攻击你们的海合组织国家。
I'm going to lob drones, rockets at you.
我要投掷无人机、火箭。
I'm going to lob rockets at Israel, okay?
我要投掷火箭到以色列，行吗？
I don't have, I don't have to strike that hard,
我没必要打得这么猛，
I just have to make, I just have to be a pain in the ass, okay?
我只要制造点麻烦，搞点小麻烦，行吗？
Because then, what happens is you're forced to come back and
于是你们就得回去应战，
bomb the living hell out of me, but guess what, I'll just hide in my mountains again, it's hide and seek, okay?
把我炸成地狱吧，但你猜怎么了，我又会躲进山里，像捉迷藏一样，行吗？
So, Iran can do this for years, and years,
于是伊朗可以这样做多年，几年，
and years, but again, remember, America is forced to win this war as fast as possible,
几年，然而记得，阿美必须尽快赢得这场战争，
because there is no political will,
因为没有政治意愿，
they don't have manufacturing capacity,
他们没有制造能力，
and they don't want to,
他们也不想这么做。
they don't want that many cats, they don't want to do any casualties, and they can make damage, okay?
他们不想有那么多的猫，他们不想造成任何伤亡，而且他们能造成损失，好吗？
Does that make sense, guys? Alright, so
这有道理吗，大家？好吧，接下来是这样：
that's all Iran's going to do, Iran's just going to be a pain in the ass, okay?
这就是伊朗要做的全部，伊朗只会是个麻烦，行吗？
A pain in the ass.
一个麻烦
It's trying to create as much economic damage as possible, it's trying to create as much fear as possible,
它正试图造成尽可能多的经济损失，正试图制造尽可能多的恐慌。
alright?
好吧？
Which will force America to attack.
这将迫使美国发动攻击。
The grand question is this,
大问题是这个，
will America launch a ground invasion, okay?
美国会发动陆战吗，行吗？
Because if it does, then I'll be in the middle of a war.
因为如果那样做，我就会陷入战争之中。
And, um, they've lost the war, okay?
而且，他们已经输了战争，行吗？
Alright? Because, look, look, look at Iran, okay?
好吧？因为，看看，看看伊朗，好吗？
Mountains and mountains, deserts,
山山山，沙沙沙，
it is impossible to occupy this country,
它占领这个国家不可能，
alright?
好吧？
It's impossible to invade, and what Iran does want to do,
不可能入侵，伊朗想做的事，
is be so, such a pain in the ass,
就是这样，真是个大麻烦，
to commit so much guerrilla warfare, that
去发动这么多游击战，
America is forced to invade, okay,
美国被迫入侵，好吗，
from over here, and from over here, and from over here,
从这里开始，从那里开始，从这里开始，
and from over here, and from over here, and over here and then eventually uh
从那里开始，从这里开始，从那里开始，最终……
but the problem is that
但问题是……
america doesn't have doesn't have the resources the political will
美国没有足够的资源和政治意愿
the manufacturing capacity to fight this war okay doesn't make sense right
制造能力去打这场战争，没道理吧
so now you're like okay i understand all this
于是你说：好的，我明白了。
but why the hell is this war happening
但这场战争到底为什么会爆发？
then if i can tell you this okay i'm sure
如果我能告诉你，我很确定……
that their generals can tell them this as well i'm sure
我确信他们的将军也能这么告诉他们
that they know that
我确信他们知道这点
this was the case in fact for years america has been planning to invade iran
这就是事实：多年来美国一直在筹划入侵伊朗
and for years the generals was like no that's suicidal let's not do this okay
于是多年来将军们说：不，这很自杀，咱们不干吧。
so why is this happening
那这为什么会发生？
and
而且
unfortunately we don't know because
不幸的是我们不知道，原因是
the administration is not telling us at first trump is like oh
政府没有告诉我们，特朗普先说了“哦”，
because the nuclear talks didn't go well but
因为核谈判不顺利
we know for a fact that
我们知道的事实是
the iranians were willing to agree to all terms of the americans
伊朗人愿意接受美国的全部条款
and then
然后
uh marco rubio who's who's who's a secretary of state
呃，马可·鲁比奥，谁，谁，谁，国务卿？
he came out yesterday he said something really moronic he said
他昨天出来说了点很糊涂的话，叫他说了……
that why did we attack iran because
他说，为什么我们要进攻伊朗？
we heard the israelis were gonna attack first
我们听说以色列人会先发攻击
and then iranians were gonna respond by attacking both the israelis
随后伊朗人会回应，先攻击以色列人再攻击我们美国人
and us the americans and therefore
于是如此
we have to preempt the israelis by
我们得先行先手打以色列
attacking first that's just retarded okay all right
先发攻击就行，没啥大事，好的，没问题
so they don't they don't know why they're doing this
他们也不知道自己为什么这么做
but there has to be a reason right okay well clue is this a clue is
但一定有原因，嗯，好吧，线索是这样，线索是…
this the soldiers are being asked the american soldiers are being asked to fight this war
士兵们被问到，美国士兵被问去打这场战争
and again no one knows why this war is happening
再说一次，没人知道这场战争为何发生
but there's reporting that
但有报道说
the generals are telling the soldiers
将军官对士兵说
this is a war
这是一场战争
for jesus this is
对耶稣来说这就是
a war to create the second
一场创造第二个
coming of jesus okay this is a German Larson and
耶稣的到来，好的，这是一位德国拉森和
he's writing this on on self -stat okay US troops were
他正在写这件事在自我-状态，好，美国军队是
told Iran war is for Armageddon the return of Jesus what is this all right
被告知伊朗战争是阿玛格顿的归来，耶稣的回归，这到底是什么？
so so sorry so
于是，我很抱歉，嗯……
so some soldiers
于是有些士兵
who are not Christians were told
他们不是基督徒被告知
that there's a war for Jesus and
有一场为耶稣而战的战争，嗯
like wait a minute we're not we're not Christians we're Muslims or we're atheists why are we fighting this war
等一下，我们不是基督徒，我们是穆斯林还是无神论者，为什么要打这场战争？
and so they let file complaint about the speech okay
于是他们让文件投诉关于演讲，好吗？
and we're going to read a part of this email
我们将阅读这封邮件的一部分
that the soldiers who
那支士兵们
are dissenting sent to some other people to complain about this okay
他们异议后被派给其他人去投诉，好吗
so um could you read please
那么，呃，你能读一下吗
I am a NCO rank withheld in our unit
我是我们部队的中士
this morning our commander opened up the combat readiness
今天早上我们的指挥官展开了作战准备状态简报
status briefing by urging us to not be afraid as
他鼓励我们不必怕
to what is happening with our combat operations in
关于我们在伊朗的作战行动正在进行的事
Iran stop okay afraid that's what tells us
停下来了，好的，害怕的那件事告诉我们了
they're losing the war okay right keep on going he urged us to tell our troops
他们正在失去这场战争，好的，继续去吧，他鼓励我们去告诉我们的部队
that this was all part of God's Divine Plan and
那是上帝神圣计划的一部分，且他特别说……
he specifically wait a minute here wait a minute God's Divine Plan God's not
他特意停顿一下，等一下，上帝神圣计划不是……
the one ordering them to fight this war it's Trump or the American military okay this is kind of weird
不是让他们打这场战争的命令是特朗普还是美国军方，这有点奇怪
and he specifically referenced numerous citations out of
他特别引用了《启示录》中的多处引文，关于末日之战和耶稣的即将归来。
the book of Revelation referring to Armageddon and
他提到《启示录》中的多处引文，关于末日之战和耶稣的即将归来。
the imminent return of Jesus Christ he said that
他特别引用了《启示录》中的多处引文，关于末日之战和耶稣的即将归来。
President Trump has been anointed by Jesus to light
特朗普总统已被耶稣膏油，点燃伊朗的火炬，发动末日之战，标志他归来
the signal fire in Iran to cause Armageddon and
伊朗的火炬已被点燃，发动末日之战，标志他归来
mark his return to Earth oh my God
哦，我的天啊
President Trump the fire in Iran it's all apart
特朗普总统，伊朗的火焰只是更大计划的一部分
of a grand plan to destroy the world
用来毁灭世界
so that Jesus will return what is this craft okay keep on going
以便耶稣归来
he had a big grin on his face on his
他脸上露出大笑容
face okay he's happy about this guys the world is ending yeah
他很开心，世界要结束了，嗯
keep on going when he said all of this which
继续说完这句
made his message seem even more crazy our
让他的发言更显疯狂，我们的指挥官很可能被描述为最初的基督徒
commander would probably be described as a Christian first
他已是这般很久了
supporter he's been this way for a very long time
supporter he's been thisway for a very long time
and makes it clear that
并且让人明白
he desires all of us under him to become just like him as a Christian
他希望我们所有人都像他一样成为基督徒
but what he did this morning was so toxic
但他今天早上所做的事真是毒气十足
and over the line that
并且在那一行上
it shocks many of us in attendance
它让在场合的许多人惊讶
at the ops readiness briefing
在作战备会议中
besides myself I am reaching out
我自己之外，我正在联系
to MRFF on behalf of 15 fellow troops I know
我代表我认识的15名同袍军人联系MRFF
you asked me about the religious views of our group who
你问我我们小组的宗教观点
has requested help from the MRFF I can only tell you
已向MRFF请求帮助，我只能告诉你
that I am Christian and at least 10 of us are Muslim and
我是基督徒，至少十人是穆斯林，另外一人是穆斯林，我不知宗教或…
one is Muslim I don't know the religious or
one is Muslim I don'tknow the religious or
non -religious status for the other three at this time okay
非宗教身份的另外三人目前情况已知
so what is happening is that
于是发生的事是这样
there's some crazy Christians in American
美国有些疯狂的基督徒
military in the American government okay
军队在美国政府中，好的
that
那
want to use this war to end the world
想用这场战争结束世界
to force Jesus to return that
让耶稣归来
is why this war is happening okay I'm not saying I'm not saying
这就是这场战争发生的原因，好的，我不是说……
that this is a reason why I'm saying like this
这就是我这么说的原因
is a possibility okay all right this is Trump
是个可能，好吧，没问题，这就是特朗普
and these are all religious leaders that support Trump because
而这些都是支持特朗普的宗教领袖
they see him as Messiah they see him as this as this great hero
他们把他视为弥赛亚，视为伟大英雄
who will cause the time of Christianity and
他将开启基督教时代
the return of Jesus and
耶稣的再来
that's a possibility as to why this war is being fought okay because
这就是这场战争打响的可能原因
quite honestly there's no other reason it's hard for me to come up with another reason okay all right
相当诚实地说，除了这个之外没有别的理由，我想不出别的理由来，没问题。
so this is something that
这就是其中一个要点。
we will look at as we go along what
我们会在过程中看……
is this crap what is Christian Zionism why would they think
这是什么玩意？基督教犹太复国主义是什么？他们为什么这么想？
that this war in the Middle East will cause the return of Jesus okay well we'll discuss this later on
那场中东战争将导致耶稣的再来，稍后我们再讨论。
but I wanted to but
我想说的是……
now it leads us to another problem which
现在它把我们带到另一个问题上，
is our entire class is
我们的整堂课就是这样，
on game theory right guys this is kind of weird because
在游戏理论上，大家好，这有点奇怪，因为
what this suggests is that
这说明了什么
religion is more important okay
宗教更重要，好的
so what's the point of game theory if people
那么游戏理论的意义是什么？
don't play by game theory it's all if they're just religious fanatics
不按游戏理论来玩，全部是他们只是宗教狂热者
all right and the answer is this and
好了，答案就是这样，答案是它仍然是游戏理论。
the answer is it's still game theory
答案是它仍然是游戏理论。
but the problem is that
但问题在于
what you think of the game
你对游戏的看法
that you think they're playing is not the game they're playing the reward that
你认为他们在玩的是游戏还是奖励
you think they want at what is not the reward that
你认为他们想要的不是那份奖励
they want okay we think in terms of material things okay
他们想要的，好的，我们从物质层面来想
so money resources power we think
所以是钱、资源、力量
that the war is being fought over these things
战争正因这些事物而展开
and
而
it's not all right the
并非全部正确
Grand secret The Grand reveal all the semester
大秘密：大揭示整个学期
all this course is this the real power the real power of war it's not
这一课的全部内容就是战争的真正力量，真正的战争力量不是战争本身，而是战争的战争，它是战争，它是战争，它是战争，你在世界上的货币不是金钱，
war it's war it's war it's war it's war Your currency in the world is not money,
war it's war it's war it's war it's warYour currency in the world is not money,
it is human consciousness.
它是人类意识。
Or basically attention.
或者说是注意力。
Okay? This is it, guys, okay?
好的？这就是了，大家，好的？
Once you understand this idea, you understand everything.
一旦你理解了这个想法，你就理解了一切。
But this is a hard idea to understand, so
但这个想法很难理解，所以……
I'll need some time to actually explain this, alright?
我需要一点时间来真正解释它，好吗？
This war is being fought
这场战争正在进行
to control the consciousness of the human race,
为了掌控人类的意识
because it is our consciousness that creates reality itself.
因为正是我们的意识创造了现实
That's the source of all wealth and all power in this world, okay?
那是这个世界所有财富和力量的源泉，明白吗？
That's why this is happening.
这就是事情发生的原因。
In other words, this is a war not just for Iran,
换句话说，这场战争不只是为了伊朗。
this is a war not just for the Middle East,
这是一场不只是中东的战争，
it is a war for the soul of humanity.
它是一场为人类灵魂而战的战争。
This is what's happening, guys.
这就是现在发生的事，大家。
Alright, this is what World War III is.
好了，三战的样子就是这样。
World War III is meant to be the last and final war of all human history,
三战本是人类历史上最后一次大冲突，
because whoever win this war will control the very soul of human existence,
谁赢了它，谁就掌握了人类存在的灵魂。
for all eternity, okay?
为永恒而已，行吗？
That is the end game.
这就是终局。
And I know this is a hard idea to understand,
我知道这很难懂。
but as we go along, I will explain this to you.
但随着进展，我会向你们解释这一点。
That is the grand secret behind the world.
那就是世界背后的大秘密。
And every night, you believe, every night, that, every night, everything that you see today, it's all an illusion.
每晚，你相信，每晚，你认为，今天你看到的一切，都是幻觉。
The reality, the truth is
现实，真相是
that consciousness is a source of all power of reality itself
意识是现实自身所有力量的源泉
and so this is a war for human consciousness,
于是这是一场人类意识的战争
it's a war for the very soul of humanity.
这是一场为人类灵魂而战的战争。
Okay? Any questions?
好的？还有问题吗？
Alright, I will see you guys next week.
好的，我下周见你们。
Bye.
再见